Hi everyone.
Today my guest
is Shubham
Saboo.
Shubham’s
track record
at the
intersection
of API products
and open source
is genuinely
extraordinary.
He's a senior
AI product
manager
at Google,
where he works
on the
AI products
that millions
of developers
build with every
single day.
His work is
largely
centered around
helping
developers
build and deploy
AI agents,
and providing
feedback
from developers
to PMs.
He's also
the creator
of the
Awesome LLM
Apps repository
on GitHub,
which has over
105,000 stars,
making it
the most
popular
collection
of AI
agent examples
ever.
On top of that,
he has published
two books,
one on GPT
three back
when it was
just released,
and another
on neural
search,
which covers
the embeddings
and vector
search
technology
that now powers
every rack
system
and AI agent
you've
ever used.
In this episode,
we'll take
a deeper
look with him
into all of
the cool
new agentic
tools
that Google
just released
from ADK 2.0
and Agent CLI
and how the
experience
of building
agents
has just
been upgraded.
Shubham,
thank you
so much
for being here
and welcome
to the
Agent Factory.
Thank you
for having me.
It's great
to be here.
Super excited
to talk to you
about this.
So Shubham
105,000 stars
on your GitHub
repository.
You know
that's just not
a vanity metric.
That's actually
105,000
developers
who looked
at your work
and they said,
you know,
I need something
like this.
So take us
back to
the beginning.
What was the
original spark
behind
the awesome
LM apps
repository?
And then
did you
also ever
imagine that
it could
lead to you
landing a PM
role at Google?
Short answer no,
I haven't
imagined
any of this
to go like that.
So to take you
back at the
beginning, when
I was
experimenting
with GV,
three
just came out
and I
was
experimenting
with the API,
I was
putting together
a lot of these
apps and samples
that I
was working
with,
experimenting
with it locally.
So I thought
like,
because I
have all these
like samples
that are
like local,
that
I'm
experimenting
with and
working with.
Maybe
I should just
structure it,
put it out there
on GitHub
and structure
it just to keep
my sanity
intact.
So whenever
I have to
reference it
back later,
I have a structured
place to go
and find it.
That was
the whole
point behind
putting
this GitHub
repository.
I haven't
thought that I
would go
go become
anything
like this.
And a few
weeks later,
when I looked
at it
like I had like
5 or 7
examples up
already,
and I saw like
30,000 stars,
which was huge
for me.
For someone who
hasn't got even
100 stars
before.
So it was a
big deal.
And that was
the moment
when I realized,
maybe
it isn't just me
who is
looking for
something
like this.
Maybe people
want stuff
like this.
People want,
really usable
actual
sample code
and examples
that they can
just run with
and use
and learn
at the
same time.
So that,
that, that,
that was
the spark
that led me
to building it
and keep
contributing it.
Like a
month later,
there was like
2000 stars.
And in
like
a few months,
I was like
5000 stars.
I was like,
okay,
this is
getting crazy.
I should,
spend
more time
with it.
I should put
more energy
to it.
So I just
started
putting together
everything
that I
was
experimenting
with, building
locally to that
GitHub repo.
And the idea
was to
just, like,
make it
open source
so that people
don't struggle
with using it
and can build
on top of it
and make
it really,
really easy
for people
to use it.
Like today,
it has
105,000 stars,
15,000 over
15,000 forks.
Which is
still like
all of
this is
unimaginable.
Like something
that I wouldn't
have thought
of before.
Because
and today, also,
it sits at,
like one of
the top 100
most start
repos of
all time.
And even made me
to like top 20
Python
developers
across the globe
multiple times.
Put that
in list.
And me
being not
a hardcore
coder coder.
So it's a
it's a huge
deal.
And that's
that's
how it all
started.
And that's
where we are
today.
It sounds like,
you know,
you are
building
publicly
and you're
initially trying
to solve
a problem
for yourself
of trying
to keep a record
of all the,
you know, fast
piecing, stuff
which was
happening at
that time.
And it just
turned into
something
really big.
And then to
add to that,
what I think
is really
fascinating is
you're not
just curating,
you're
also building
at Google.
You've
written books,
you've seen
the entire arc
from GPT three
to where
we are now,
at with
Asiatic AI.
So how has your
perspective on,
you know,
what makes
a good
AI agent changed
from when
you wrote
that book
initially
to today
at Google?
It's an
interesting
question.
Previously,
it wasn't
even an AI.
I mean,
like today,
we all know it
as AI origins.
It started
feedback
with machine
learning.
With GPT three.
It introduced
the concept
of a large
language model,
which is and the
AI model
that we use
as part of
our agent.
And three
years ago,
if I go back
and look at it,
the entire graph
was prompt
engineering.
So I don't know
if you
remember that
GPT three UI,
where you
have to put
an like
system
instruction
prompt,
structure it
in a way
just to
make sure
that you
get something
out of the model
that you want.
So previously,
the art was
just making sure
you get
something
out of the model
that you want.
And
that would be
referred
as prompt
engineering.
So back then,
if I have to
spend time
to get spend
an afternoon
getting
structured Json
or something
like that,
but today
it's as easy
as passing
a Python
text schema
and it
just works.
So a lot
is changed
now, like, back
then, back
then, like agent
was just
a janky loop
around
a completion
call with some
string parsing.
Today,
I have six
agents running
on a cron job
that does,
all the work
for me.
What hasn't
really changed
is,
the people
who are shipping
the most useful
apps are
the ones
who understand
the users
and the
problems.
The model is
a universal
function now,
so the model is
table stakes.
Everybody has
the model.
Model?
This produces
whatever
you want.
You don't really
have to struggle
with prompt
engineering.
And come up
with those,
like,
magic words
to get something
out of
the model.
Your only job
now is to shape
the problem
so that the
universal
function
that you have
as something
meaningful
to work with.
So everybody has
access to model.
But the people
who are winning
today
or outstripping
the others are
the people
who understand
the problems
better,
people
who understand
their users
better.
That was true
in GPT
three era
as well.
So your prompt
is as good
as your
understanding
of, the problem
that you're
solving
or understanding
of the users
and problems
that you're
working with.
That's even
more true
now, because
now everybody,
pretty much
everybody
has access
to these models
and agents.
So model
is table stakes.
Everything around
this is hardness,
which we
all sort of
and in
combination
in total
becomes agent.
Everybody
has access
to that.
But what has
become more
important is
how do you
communicate
with your agent.
How do you talk
to your agent?
Do
you understand
the users
that you're
solving for?
Do
you understand
the problem
that you have
and can you
shape that?
So all of these
skills
were important.
Today
has become more
and more
important.
We have come
all the way
from making
sure,
we hammered
the model to up
to a way
that it
can produce
the output
that we want,
to an agent,
which is super,
super smart.
And the only
limitation now
is how creative
you can get
with it.
Like how clearly
you can think
about the
problem.
That's
where yeah,
I love that.
And I
actually like
we like the take
that you have on
how we went
from something
super simple
of prompt
engineering,
like you said,
to where
we're right
now at
and how
there's
certain skills
which have like
stuck around
as being
super important,
no matter
which stage
we were at.
So I've
heard a lot
about agent CLI,
and I'm
super excited
to see you
demoing this
for us.
Could you
explain what
exactly is
agent CLI
and how can
people start
building
with it?
Yeah.
So agent
CLI and
Agent platform
is a client.
Skills packages
combine
to give
the models
your coding
agent.
You can use it.
First of all
you can use it
with any coding
agent
Gemini CLI code
codex
or any
other
coding agent
that you would
like.
But
what happened
before is
when you ask
those coding
agent to build,
agents
and SDK,
it might
hallucinate
at times
or it might
come up with
buggy code.
But agents here
like really
fix this,
that it is
a combo
or it is
a package
of like,
and skills
for building,
evaluating
and deploying AI
agents on Google
Cloud
agent platform.
So everything
packaged into
a single CLI,
all you need
to do
is just like set
up, install
one command
once you do this
and it will,
you can do it
in your
terminal.
It will be
globally
picked up
by any of your
coding agents.
And just like
that,
automagically,
your coding
agents
have access
to all
the internal
tools,
the code base
and knowledge
about SDK
and building
agents
from their agent
CLI handles
everything like
scaffolding
your agents.
If you want
to ever use
URLs on
cloud Google
Cloud Platform,
it can do that
just from
simple
English prompts.
It can deploy it
in simple
command.
You can add
observability,
can do all these
things.
The simplest way
to use agent CLA
is through
a coding agent.
But if you don't
want to use
a coding agent,
you can just try
to use,
CLI commands
and it packages
all these skills
that you see
here,
like so,
and skills
package,
which pretty
much covers
the entire
agent
development
lifecycle.
And to see that
in action,
let's actually
get into
the terminal
and build
our first agent
using agents.
Yet like
so what
we'll do is
we can
just follow this
simple tutorial
to get started
with.
It's a caveman
compressor.
An interesting
example.
The season takes
verbose text
and grunts
it down
to caveman
style summaries,
which is
kind of fun.
So to
get started,
all you have
to do is
copy this
command
and run it
in your
terminal,
and then
you can open
any of
your coaching
coding agent.
As mentioned
before,
you can
use Gemini's
like Cloud
Code Codex
or any
other agent.
So I've already
run the
UX command
to install
the agent CLI
opened up
a coding agent.
Again,
you can use
any coding agent
that you
would like.
I've opened up
Gemini CLI
and we can
just get
started.
That's all
it needed.
So if I give it
this prompt,
use agent CLI
to build
a caveman style
agent
that compresses
verbose
text into
technical
grants.
It can just
start executing
just like that,
and you'll
see it
picking up
these agent
skills
from agent
client scaffold.
So
it is working.
The install
is working fine.
Will allow it,
and it will
keep building.
It will
automatically
build
the agent
files and
put it in
this directory.
Here
I've created
this agent CLI
demo folder
under
my desktop.
And all you have
to do
is just
like allow
a lot of
lines of
some commands.
So here you see
it has
created this
new folder
called Caveman
Agent
Install Agency.
L-I used
all the skills
that it wanted.
And in
maybe less
than a minute,
you'll have
something up
and running
smoother.
I remember
you were
asking me
why agent CLI
in the
beginning.
This is,
the real
use case.
This is
what you get
out of the box.
Pretty
much everything.
Right
along with
the code.
You get
the environment,
you get
everything that
you just need
to get
started with.
And then
you can just
once it is
complete,
you can just ask
the agent itself
to run the app,
fire it locally.
So here we see
it has already completed
it has built
the caveman
agent using
agent CLI.
All these files
are in there.
It has also
tested it out
here.
You can see
it has provided
this verbose
input
and our caveman
agent
has converted
into this.
This is funny.
And we can also
tested with
the web UI.
All I have
to do is
run this
like this is
actually huge.
So I think
just like a
couple months
back,
what I would use
to do
when I was
using Gemini,
I am trying
to build agents,
I'm using 80
K, I would
copy paste
like stuff
from the
SDK docs
to Gemini C,
like to give it
more context,
but I think now
I can skip
all of that
because we have
that
prepackaged.
Yeah, yeah.
And here you
see by the time
you are
talking Smitha,
it has already
opened up
the web
UI and it
is already
running on
our localhost
at this point.
But before
we get to that,
let me start
the deployment
process
so you can like
you can
deploy it
on Agent Engine,
but you can
also ask
the agent
what all
deployment
options
that you have,
to really
understand
what
you could do
with it.
So please
help me
understand
the deployment
options
available
for my project.
It
will figure out
and give you
all the info
that you need,
and then
you can select
which deployment
option
that you would
want to
use here.
You see.
So it is like
actually having
and senior
engineer
working
alongside you
to really give
you guidance
whenever you
get stuck or it
it just works
for learning
as well. Right.
Let's say
if I'm
deploying it
for the
first time
in the Google
ecosystem,
Google
Cloud ecosystem,
and I don't know
what my,
deployment
options are,
all I can do
is just prompt
it here
and I get
these three
options.
It also tells me
what it is
best for,
how it works,
the cost
all these things.
And then
all I can
say is deploy
to agent Engine.
If you remember,
Agent Engine
is a deployment
runtime for,
deploying
AI agents
on agent
platform
that we
looked at
that when we
talked about
the resume and
the agents.
So it will
do the
deployment.
It normally
takes around 5
to 10 minutes.
That's why we,
give it
this command.
Are you ready
to deploy
to give an agent
to the
environment?
Yes.
And the
good thing is,
it always asks
for explicit
approval
when you ask it
to interact
with these
external
services.
Now, it will
automatically
deploy
to Agent Engine
in next
five minutes.
We can come back
to that.
But,
it's not
going to
just like,
power up
a bunch of
cloud services
without you
not knowing.
So that's great.
Yeah, yeah.
And,
the other
great thing
about it
is you
really don't
have to leave
your terminal
to get all of
these
things done
before.
You would have
to go to Cloud
Console,
look at the
agent engine,
maybe run
a few commands,
go and read
the talk.
And even if you
were using
coding agent,
you have to
like give
multiple docs
link or connect
MCP servers
and whatnot,
right?
It was kind
of a mess.
Eden
CLI really
brings it
all together.
Obviously.
Also all of the
config files,
the Yaml
files, it's
taking care
of all of that.
In order
to do
all of that
and
your environment
and everything.
Right.
So we can go
to this link
the localhost
with port 8080
and see
this
come to life.
So
the cool thing
about it
is you get this
nice and
sleek web
UI to test
your agents
before
you put them
in production.
This is available
locally.
This is
running on my,
local
environment,
as we saw
before in
the terminal.
And here I can
just open
this up
to test it out.
I can just
like this.
You see here,
you see the
nice chat
bot that
I've got.
I can send
the message.
Hi to our
caveman agent
and see
what it replies.
Okay, how
are you doing?
Maybe.
And here
you see
on the side
panel
you can see
all these
events,
as we are
chatting, it is,
taking
logs of
all the events
that are
working here.
You can see
the states
artifacts.
All these
things are
available,
which will help
a developer
to get the
full
understanding
of how
the agent
is working,
what all features
are available,
and
what they can
do with it.
And let's
now go back
and see
where our
deployment is.
Is it
already deployed
or not?
And then
I can show you
how it
looks like
when the agent
is deployed
through
each
intervention.
So we got this
link.
We will just
paste it
in our browser
and see what
that looks like
in Cloud
Console.
So to
remind what
we did so far,
we installed
the agent
CLI open.
Gemini coding
agent Gemini,
click
in our terminal.
Just put a
simple prompt
to build that
caveman agent.
It was built.
Then we open up
the SDK web
UI to
test it out,
all through
our terminal
without leaving
our terminal.
We got
all of this
done.
We gave
a simple command
to deploy it on
Agent Engine,
and
our deployment
is complete.
This is where
we are.
Before we go
and look at
the deployment,
let's do
another cool
thing here.
So
the next thing
that you
would want
to do with
your agent
is maybe
evaluate,
right, evaluate,
how
they are doing.
So maybe
we can ask
the coding agent
to come up with
different eval
criteria for
government agent
and run them
for us to see
how it's
working.
And this
is really
important
for anything
that you're
putting in
production to
really have
evals ready.
And now
with agent CLI
your coding
agent can do
that for you.
So
meanwhile this
command runs
what we can do
is go to
our browser.
So I just open
this link
in our browser.
Here you can see
this caveman
agent
being deployed.
You can see
the dashboard.
the traces
identity.
All the
production
ready features
just plugged in
through a
single
deployment.
You even have
a playground
here
to test it out.
I
and
the same thing
that we saw
in the local web
UI is also
available
in the cloud
console.
You can
look at all
these logs here.
You can see
the caveman
agent replying
and this service
is now
accessible,
for anyone
to everyone,
you can
just like share
the deployment
endpoint and
things could
be built
on top of that.
So we are here.
Next thing
let's look at
the status
of evil
sap evil
URLs that we
asked the agent
to generate.
We asked
the agent
to generate
like 20 evil
criteria for
We asked the
coding agent
to generate
20 evil
criteria.
Lots of agents
like building
agents
with the agents,
generate,
20 evil
criterias.
And here,
you see,
it has generated
all these
evil criterias.
And the best
thing about
this is it
won't only
generate
the evil
criterias, but
also test
the agent
against those
evil criterias.
Take a minute
or two to
do that.
We can come back
to it later.
And the
next thing
that you could
really do
here is extend
your agent.
I want to go
back to the docs
and show you how
you can extend
the
functionalities
of your
functionality of
the simple
caveman agent
that we built,
through simple
prompts
all the way
to the bottom.
We have build
agent.
We,
we have already
deployed
the agent
on agent Engine.
We are.
We have asked
the agent to
write emails
and it is
already
running them
for us.
Next thing
that you
would want
to do is,
tools to
your agent.
So to add a
Google search
tool
to your agent,
all you need
to do
is just add this
like
simple prompt
and it will
automatically
add Google
search to
your agent.
If you want to
make your agent
workflow
multi-agent
and add
more agents,
you can use
the smaller
agent from.
You can build
a drag
agent where
you could have
grounding
in your docs
or
in your database.
So we have all
these templates
which lets us,
which lets agent
CLI create,
these agents.
And pretty much
99% of times,
I should say
99% of
the times,
in one shot.
So
the next thing
that we
will look
is how you can
add a Google
search tool.
So, give
an agent,
have access
to current
events,
and
it has access
to internet,
which makes it
even more fun.
But
what you can do
is actually,
add any of
these tools
and integrations
that we talked
about here.
All these tools
are available
at your disposal
here.
You see the
agent generated
these emails,
tested it
for us.
And the
good thing
is all
the emails
are passed.
If something
hasn't passed,
it will flag
them as fail.
And
what you would do
then is again,
ask your coding
agent what fail
and what we can
do to fix them.
But
the next thing
that I want
to show you
here is how
you can add
a tool
to your agent.
It's as
simple as this,
so it will have
all the
context of,
adding a tool.
What kind of
tools exist
in the
agent ecosystem?
What are the
syntax for
adding
these tools
and just works
here?
You see,
this is adding
tool in real
time as
we speak.
And once
it adds
the tool,
we can ask it
to restart
the local
version to pick
up the changes.
It will
automatically
run a
smoke test
for us.
Yeah.
So here
you see, it is,
writing
the code
for adding
Google
search tool.
And not only
it writes
the code,
it also does
a smoke
test for us.
So we know that
it is working.
Here it is.
Ask the question
about the latest
model news.
And the cavemen
responded in
its own
language,
which is
super caveman
ish model
was hot by more.
It's 100.
It's one
good advice.
Of course
we need
more compute.
Yeah, yeah.
So yeah,
overall,
this is working.
Just to recap,
we
built an agent.
We deployed
it on
Agent Engine.
We ran a local
version through
LDK web
UI to
test it out.
We created
emails,
we added tools.
All of this
in what,
like ten minutes
better.
So this is
super exciting.
It seems
that it's easier
now than ever
to build agents.
And I can see
a lot
of developers
being really
excited
about this.
I especially
I noticed
how easy it is
to deploy this
from your
local machine,
where you're
building it
with a coding
Asian
like Gemini
CLI directly
onto the cloud.
That's awesome.
I think
this is a huge
game changer.
You also
mentioned
multi-agent
systems.
So could we
look at your
next demo
on building
a multi
agent roster
using agent CLI?
I'm super
pumped for this.
Yeah.
That's a
that's
a fun one.
Let's just head
back to our
Gemini CLI
and let me paste
this prompt.
So
and while
it works
on the prompt
let me go
through what
this is.
Here is
what I prompted
the agent
CLI to.
I'm likely to
build a multi
agent roster
using JDK
and Gemini.
What it will do
is create
an Streamlit app
for two,
engage
in one
agent will,
just
go to GitHub,
analyze an PR.
All we have to do
is just wrap up
the URL,
pull
request URL.
It will go
and
automatically
analyze the PR
for good
quality bugs,
security,
performance,
all the
standard things.
So one
agent will
just act
as a code
analyst
or code
reviewer.
And the second
second agent,
which is the fun
part,
will be our
host master.
Based on
the analysis
that we get
from our
first agent,
what we'll do
is we'll create
a roast
and a meme
prompt
for nano banana
to generate
an image.
So
that meme from
will go into
the nano banana.
Gemini.
Flash
image model,
and it
will generate
a meme
at the end.
So this is how
the workflow
will
hopefully work
once agency
alive will
generate.
The thing
for us.
And here
it is
giving us like
some options.
You can choose
like any of
these
options like
go with
the Streamlit
orchestration
and then
it will run for
a few minutes
and create
an app.
What to save us?
Some time.
What I
already did is
prompted it
before of this
call, and
created the app.
Saved it
to a GitHub
repo.
Let's look
at the code
and also
deployed it
through
agent CLI.
Then we can
look at the
deployed version
and see how
it really works.
And maybe
you can
give me a PR
that you want me
to roast,
that you want,
our agent
to roast
and we can have
some fun.
Sounds good.
I actually have,
like two PRS
pulled up,
which
would be great
to roast,
which I recently
created.
So. Yeah.
So as mentioned,
this is how
it would work.
It also created
cherry on
the top.
It also created
a read me
for me
to explain to
you guys
what this app
or this,
multi-agent app
would do.
We have a code
analyst
which is
analyzing
the code,
which is feeding
into the roast
master,
and roast
master writes
jokes
meme prompt
and give
a verdict
just like
a score
on how good the
PR is.
And then
in the end,
based on
the meme from
the nano banana
image model
Gemini
image model,
which will read
the meme for us.
So this is
what the
deployed version
or the fully
built up app
looks like.
Simple
prototype,
but really
fun idea.
All you have
to do
is just enter
your Gemini
key here.
GitHub
token optional
if you want.
You can put it
here.
Depends on the
traffic limiting
and all
we need to do
is just drop
a PR thing
and let me share
like what
this PR
is about.
Like this
was the
this is the
PR that we got
from samples
repo submit
that you created
this.
Let's
see what
it comes
up with.
This is
interesting.
I'm excited
about this one.
I'm very
curious
to see this
being roasted.
I've
honestly not
had any of my
PR roasted,
besides,
obviously from
other software
engineers.
So let's see.
It would be nice
to get it
roasted by an
actual AI agent.
Awesome,
awesome.
And the
roast is
already in
the run.
The PR
it reviewed it
just like any
technical review
it would.
So code
quality
looking good.
Not a lot of
logical issues
and bugs.
This is looking
good as well.
So pretty good.
Smell like
you got a 9.2
out of nine
out of two
I think
that's great.
Yeah nine
out of ten
9.2 out of ten
was pretty good.
Pretty good.
Let's look
at the roast
and you
tell me
if this is funny
or not okay.
So calling
load dot e.
And we twice
in the coding
environment
of checking
if you
is checking
if you lock
the front door
walking to
your car
and then going
back to check
again while
your house is.
Because of
your error
handling
okay okay.
Fair enough.
Did you know
about this one?
But is this.
No. So setting.
Oh, I set
the maps
API key equals
to no API
found in
the set.
Yeah,
I should have
used like
a normal,
you know,
interesting.
I know
you didn't
copy, but. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
This
this is funny.
Basically,
when you
can gaslight
the NCP tool
into an auto
midlife crisis
at with you.
Okay.
Fair enough.
Hardcoding Gemma
not your fault.
It's a very
good model.
So.
Yeah,
I'll go
with that.
Yeah,
but this is
funny.
That's true.
Oh,
interesting.
Okay, now
look at the
let's
look at the meme
that I generate.
Okay.
So.
Fair enough.
Final verdict
is here.
You build
a Ferrari,
but try
to fuel it
with a
sticky note
that says
gasoline
not found,
which is a
reference to
this one. Funny.
Oh my god.
Okay,
this was a
really
weird roast,
so hopefully the
agent is
working.
Agent CLA is
doing his thing
and we
successfully
created our
first
multi-agent,
without even
getting into
an ID.
So we did
all of this
without getting
into an ID,
all from
terminal
coding agent,
amazing CLI
to the
walking app
that is
deployed,
online,
which is
pretty crazy
and
pretty insane.
If you were
to ask me, like,
can you do this?
Like,
if you would
ask me
six months ago,
is it possible
I would like
maybe,
but now
we can do it.
Which is super
crazy
and interesting.
This is so cool.
And I think
this would
be great
for people
to check out.
Is this
something
that they
can build
using
your prompt?
Is there
is this
prompt available
on the ATP
docs website?
So we
will be open
sourcing
the GitHub repo
that we
looked at.
And
what we will do
is just
like drop
the prompt
in there
because here's
the code prompt.
History is
the new code.
All you need is
prompt
to regenerate
the code.
Nice. Okay.
Link in
the description
box below
if you're
interested
in also getting
your eyes
frozen like me,
so you can
check that
off and build
it yourself.
Google Cloud
Next just ended
and Google
announced
some really
massive updates
and you
are at the
forefront
of this.
So let's talk
a little bit
about 80 K 2.0
building
production grade
autonomous
agents
with 80 K.
And then also
super cool,
the new
agent CLI
in Gemini
Enterprise
Asian platform.
What does the
new framework
unlock
for developers.
Yeah.
So we introduced
quite
a few things
at Google Cloud
next this year.
And one
of the most
fascinating ones
is 82.0,
something that
I'm generally
excited about.
Let me walk
you through
some of
the interesting
things
that comes
with 82.0.
So first one
that you see on
the screen
is graph based
agent workflows.
Now why
do you need
graph based
agent workflows
when you can
just stuff,
everything
in an agent
or a multi-agent
you have,
like your
instruction
model and tools
and what
it has
been working for
a while. Right.
But before
you would define
what would happen
previously is
you would define
your multi-agent
workflow mostly
through prompts.
It work,
but then
you would see
your agent start
taking shortcuts
after several
turns or start
becoming lazy.
What some people
would call,
okay,
my agent has
become lazy.
I have all this
context in,
but by the time
it gets to 5 or
7, turn it.
Forget
what it did
in the first.
Don't forget
that has access
to some
of the tools.
So that's
the problem
that most
of the agents
suffer
in production
environment.
It would forget
the rules.
I would forget
the tools
that it would
have access to.
But with graph
based workflows,
what you can do
is now
explicitly
draw the flow
of your agent.
What that
means is
the parts
that need
to be
deterministic
and stay
deterministic,
like compliance
checks, right,
where you don't
really need
an intelligence
or,
an agent
to really
champion.
It's a
straightforward
logic
which needs
to stay as is.
And it is
very important
that,
the logic stays
deterministic
and does
not change
with agent,
running it
for five times
or seven times
or 100 times.
Right.
And the parts
where you want
the model's
judgment,
those are
reasoning nodes.
That's
where you
could have
the model decide
and dynamically
take those
decisions.
So the same
workflow
gives you access
to both kind
of logics,
which you can
put together
and have it
run in
your production
environment.
It's a pretty
clean pattern.
Once you see it,
you get
the flexibility
of an agent.
Along with
the
deterministic,
workflow
or the
reliability of
function
where
you need it.
The second
thing that
I want to
show you
is the changes
that we made
to Agent
Runtime.
Two features
that I'm really
excited about
is inventory
agents
and resume
agents.
And
why do they matter.
So most of the
agent moves
that
you would see
are 32nd
demos or
two minute
demos where,
you know,
you you'll see
agent running
in a loop
for a minute
or two
and then it does
the task like,
it completes
the task
and then
just like,
turns off,
but this is way
far from
the production.
Reality
production
agents
sometimes have
to run for
hours and hours
and maybe days
at times.
When a user
has something,
the agent calls
a few tools it.
And so
it's done.
Production
doesn't really
look like that
production
environment
normally has.
Stop
connections,
services
that go down,
some events
that are
fighting it to
M workflows
that spend
hours or days.
So these are
two features
that help
any production
agent survive
that reality.
Let's look
at the resume
agent first.
So what what
that really is
resume
is actually
what it
sounds like
if your agent
gets interrupted
and network
drops, a service
goes down
or whatever,
it picks up
where it
actually
left off,
you just flip
a flag
on top of
app config
and it
just works.
It tracks
which tools
already
ran, skips
them, continues
from the break
before
you would,
you would have
to restart
everything
from scratch.
But now
your agents
can just resume
where they
left off.
It's
pretty cool.
Really cool.
I mean, it's
just like one
line of code
or like,
one flag
that you need
to just
one spot.
Yeah, it's
it's just this,
like, is resume
true?
That's
that's all
you need to do.
And your agents
can resume
at specific
intervals
when something
breaks.
Now moving on
to the
even cooler
part,
the inventory
agents.
So I guess,
all of you
might have heard
about open
claw agents.
All these,
like,
autonomous
agents that
run for days
and days
like I myself
run an agent
team like 60.
Yeah.
Agent team
using open claw.
It runs
24 over seven
doing all kind
of stuff for me.
So
how do you build
something
like that
which is
customized
for your
enterprise,
environment,
that can do
the specific
job reliably,
reliably being
the keyword
here.
That can do
the specific job
for you
reliably
in your
production
environment.
Event agents
is the way
to do that.
These are
the agents
that these
are actors.
So,
I want to take
a step back
here.
Like, normally
you would
have an agent,
you would run it
in production
and you
would have,
like, specific
things to do.
But agents are
only as smart
as your
trigger to
it, right?
You would want
these agents
to autonomously
execute.
You would want
these agents
to decide
and have like
some trigger
events
which execute
or trigger them.
These are
the agents.
Event agents
are the agents
that react
to those events
without you
prompting them.
If you're
prompting them,
maybe
your agent
is not
that
intelligent,
but
when your agent
is deciding
to execute
themselves
based on
certain
triggers,
it is
becoming more
like human.
And this is
becoming
more ambient
and intelligent,
more
proactive
than reactive.
So with emergent
agents,
what you can do
is you can
have them
trigger to a
specific event.
It could be
a pub
sub message
coming in,
and your
agent runs
a file, lands
in your cloud
storage
or in your
local drive,
and it
runs certain
agent workflows.
Or there's
a cron job
which you
can set.
And at that
specific time
you can
your agents
or agent, team
or whatever
your logic is,
it runs
automatically.
So you get
concurrency
limits, retries
that later
queues
all of that
out of the box
before
you have
to write
all of this
yourself.
And even
with that,
you would
not really have
something
that would be
proactive
in nature.
And
the last thing
that I want
to, talk
about is
ADX support
for multiple
languages.
It is one of
the frameworks
which is true
multi-language
in nature.
We have Python,
we have
TypeScript,
we have Go
and Java.
So really
meeting
developers
where they are,
you don't
really need
to learn Python
to move
everything
to Python.
Use a production
great
agent workflow.
You can use it
in the language
that you like,
or you can
use it
in the language
that your
existing
workflows are.
That
really opens up
a lot of teams
who weren't
going to rewrite
the stack
for building
agents.
Now, anyone
and everyone
can just build
production
agents,
using these,
languages,
using
the languages
that they would
like, I think.
And the next,
I can
just envision
so many
developers
being excited
about all of
these SDKs
for 80 K now,
and also,
I just love
the look of
the new 80
k.dev website.
It's great.
Awesome.
Thank you
so much.
And all of
these are
open source.
So if you are,
geek
or if you
are really
interested in
looking at the
source code,
all you need
to do
is just
like click
any of these
repo
and you can
actually see
the source code.
So all of these
wrappers are
open source.
You can look at
the source code
and you can
build and extend
on top of this
framework
as well.
That's the cool
thing about it
that I really,
really like.
And the
next thing
that I want
to talk to
you about
is the open
source ecosystem
that we have
built
around SDK.
So what we did
is actually
went out
and asked
developers
the tools
that they would
want to use,
not just
Google tools,
anything
and everything
that they would
want to use
with the region.
So what we did
is
we put together
an open
ecosystem
of tools
and plugins,
which you
can use
with Ada,
with your
agents,
with just
a line of code
or a few
lines of code.
Right.
Shubham,
you know,
looking through
your recent
publications
on ECS,
which are doing
a great job
off, by the way,
thank you.
And I see
a lot of
your posts
going viral
all the time.
So you've
been dropping
some serious
knowledge bombs.
I want to dig
into a few
of your
core
philosophies,
especially your
thoughts on
Open Claw
and what
it's like,
being a PM
building
AI for AI.
As you've
mentioned
many times.
Yeah,
interesting.
So let's
start with
the open
claw one.
Just
for the context,
for people
who don't know,
I run a six
AI agent team
with Open Claw
that works
for me 24/7,
pretty much
handling
anything
that I do
outside Google.
So managing my
social media
newsletter,
there
is an
engineering
agent called Ros
who actively
manages
the awesome
apps open
source repo.
He makes sure
all the
people are stuck
friends
inspired.
I have to ask.
Yeah,
yeah, yeah.
So yeah,
he had a fun
story.
It all started
with Monica
being my chief
of staff,
so mainly agent,
when I
was creating,
installing Open
Claw.
It starts
with
the first agent,
which is your
meaning.
And I was like,
what should be
my first agent?
It's like, okay,
because
I really
like friends
in the office.
I was like,
let it be
Monica.
So Monica
became.
That's how
Monica became
my chief
of staff.
I did not
started,
with the idea
of running
multi-agent
team,
but as the use
cases expanded,
as we had,
agents had
more context.
It's me
and my
agent working
through
the process
of deciding
how our
agent arc
looks like,
what our agent
Arc
should look like.
And that's
the fun
part, right?
When you
start with
something
like Open Claw,
you are
so much bought
into the hype
cycle.
You look at all
the fancy
demos on X
and YouTube
and you're like,
okay,
this is the thing.
Like I
install
Open Claw
and it will
change my life.
And just
so people
install it,
they fire up
their
first agent.
And from
the get go,
they started
asking
some very
specific
questions
and get
garbage output.
Right.
They expect
magic but
get mediocre
output,
and then
they blame
the framework.
They're like,
oh no, that's
not great.
It's not
working.
And I see
these kind
of people
operating in
two extremes.
One is people
who would
not give
any context.
They are
super excited,
because they're
directly coming
from X
and YouTube.
They're like,
okay,
I'll do this
install,
get started.
And that's
like, oh,
this does not
work for me
because
you haven't
given
any context
to your agent
or to
your model.
It does not do
anything
specific
about you.
It's a
generic model,
generic agent.
So expect
generic answers.
And then
there are people
on the other
side of extremes
which will be like,
okay,
let me give this
agent context.
Let me
dump everything
that I have
on me,
on my company,
all the like
five, 1000 files
under the agent.
Then you're
doing
context plot.
So treat agents
like you're
like a human,
because when
you do
the context
plot, it becomes
really, really
difficult
for the agent
to figure out,
what
are you
specifically
looking for?
And it becomes
really,
really difficult
for agent,
to figure out,
like,
what is the
specific,
information
that really
matters?
The agent
turns in
context.
It cannot
really tell.
Tell what
matters
from what data.
So the fix is
really simple
here.
It's pretty much
how you
would onboard
an intern
or a new
employee.
You don't dump
the entire
company's
information,
to them
on day one.
You tell them
who you are,
what you do,
what do you
need?
From them,
you start
simple,
you start slow,
and then
you build
from that
in their
own right.
You slowly
build on
top of that,
the agents
learn
through you.
The.
The best way
that I found
this to
be working
is that the
agent interview
you ask
you follow up
question
to learn
about you.
And that's
the process.
That worked
with me
and Monica
when I
created Monica,
she started
asking
me question,
what
can I do for you?
What do you like,
what you don't
like?
And slowly
giving this
very specific
context,
she started
building
something called
Soul File.
Her personality.
So soul,
soul
file is a very
specific file
which helps
agent to decide
what their
personality is.
And through this
conversation,
Monica
automatically
started
adding things,
adding things
in her soul file
and whatever
she's learning
on me
or about me.
She started
putting it
together in user
dot MD5.
So agent
is already
very smart.
It's how you
deal with them.
They've already
started like
she's already
started
figuring out
how to structure
the information,
where to
put what,
and how to
make sense
out
of these things.
But
the only thing
that
really mattered
here is the
specific context
that you give
to your agent.
So treating
your open
agents
as an employee
is the only fix.
It
seems difficult,
but it is
not really
that difficult.
It is just
like talking
to your agents,
onboarding them
as a real
employee.
So based on
what you're
saying,
it seems
that
communication
is more
important
than ever.
Now, a
lot of people
assume that,
you know,
when you're
working with
AI agents
or working
with AI
in general,
you don't have
to communicate
or
overcommunicate
like you would
when you are
dealing
with humans,
but that seems
to not be
the case.
It seems that,
you know,
you do want
to
overcommunicate
and
communication
is more
important
than ever.
Yeah, yeah, I,
I mean
to normally
summarize
whenever I
tell these
things
to people,
like soft
skills
are becoming
more important
than you would
think.
Basic skills
like
communication,
understanding
the problem,
user empathy,
all of these
are becoming
really,
really important
because
the technical
part for agents
is either
being solved
or getting
solved.
But
the only part
that would
remain
is how you would
interact
with them,
how you would
deal with them.
Just like the
simple example
that we
solve with
setting up
the open floor.
Agent Monica.
Right.
It could be
worse,
or it could be
really good,
depending on
how you
communicate
with them,
how you interact
with them.
So that's really
the key here.
You're also
a senior
AI product
manager
at Google,
but you are
specifically
working in
what people
call,
you know, the
AI of AI space,
building
AI dev tools
that are
explicitly
designed
to build
other agents.
So what is it
like managing
products
where, you know,
the end user
isn't just
a human
developer,
but another AI?
And can
you talk
a little bit
more about that?
Yeah, yeah.
So something
started shifting
almost,
last year
or like the end
of last year
when the users
of your product
and not only
just humans,
they are also agents.
Because when
we build
all these
sophisticated
systems,
what would you
expect to happen
next? Right.
The agents
will build
agents
themselves.
Right.
And in
this episode
itself,
we talked about
agents like
the Gemini CLI
with the agent
CLI using tools,
deploying on
agent engines.
There was no
human
interaction
between,
human
interaction
required
for using
those services.
There was no
human
interaction
required for me
to build agents,
to deploy agents
to run eyeballs.
All of them
were agents,
building agents.
Right.
So when
we are designing
these products,
we have to
keep in mind
that humans are
not the only
user anymore.
And that changes
a lot of things.
Human
user would
tolerate a
little bit
of slow
onboarding.
They may,
read help
text when
they are
confused.
But
when it comes
to an agent,
they just pass
to the
first thing
that they see.
Every interface.
Your design
has to work
for humans
as well
as agents.
Let's have
some fun.
Rapid fire.
I'll give you
a statement
and you tell me.
Agree.
Disagree,
or it's
complicated.
And then also
you give me
a quick reason
like ready?
Let's go. Yeah.
Rag is dead.
And fine
tuning is
a feature. Damn.
I would say
the wrong.
It's a it's
a wrong framing.
It used to
make sense
a year ago,
I would
reframe it as,
rag versus
long context
because Karpathy
became
not sure
if you're
following,
but recently
car parties
introduced
Karpathy
this idea of a
let me give
just kind of
your second
brain
with structures,
everything that
you've
been doing
and reading,
and it showed
how you can
skip track
with
long context.
So I would say
the debate is
more around
track versus
long context
now.
And yes,
it's
complicated.
The best
AI agent
architecture
is the
simplest one
that works 100%
like I've
reviewed
a lot of,
apps,
chat apps,
assistant
AI agents
over the course
of last
two years.
The ones
that gets
most popular
are the ones
that have
the simplest
architecture.
So people
should be able
to run it.
They should be able
to understand
the code
that it has,
all of that
in the easiest
way possible.
So simplest
architecture
always wins.
Open source
AI models
will surpass
proprietary
models within
two years.
Complicated.
On specific
benchmarks,
maybe open
source is
catching up
in a big way.
So it is
getting better
and better.
What we saw
with Quinn and
Jamal for.
But I
would envision
a future
where 80%
of your
use cases
would be done
by open
source model,
but still
you would
rely on
frontier closed
source model
for 20%
of the
use cases,
which might
not be something
that everybody
need.
But which
would be
something
that's like
state of
the art,
highly complex
logical
reasoning tasks.
You would still
rely on,
closed
source models.
So complicated.
But open
source is
getting there.
Okay.
I think
that's like
a very
hot topic.
So a lot of
people will
be interested.
Every developer
needs
to understand
embeddings and
vector search
I agree.
So if you're
building
anything
with memory
retrieval,
personalization,
you're touching
embedding.
You really don't
need to be,
math wizard
to understand
embedding.
I'm not asking
you to,
like, understand
from a
static
statistical
point of view,
but at least
understand
the core
concepts.
At least
understand
what changes
when you change
chunk size
or when hybrid
search beats.
But vector
search is having
a basic
understanding
of these
concepts.
Why cosine
similarity is
not always
the best metric.
All these
things,
makes a lot
of sense,
even
specifically
more so
in the
agent world
where memory
is the key
layer,
where retrieval
is more
important
than ever.
I agree
strongly agree
that people
should
understand
and really learn
about
embeddings.
Vector
databases,
vector.
So it's
debatable.
But embeddings?
Yes, 100%
I agents
are overhyped
and most
use cases just
need a
good prompt.
It's,
rich
coming from me.
Yes,
most use
cases can
just do
with a good
prompt to,
single
API call.
You don't really
always need
an agent
for everything.
I know
it's a hot
topic,
and everybody
just wants
to build. Yeah.
Agent
for anything
and everything
they want to do.
Just like
for caveman,
we built an agent.
We did not
have to.
But just to
show a concept.
We did, but
you don't
really have
to build
agent
every time.
Like,
if you can
get away
with a
simple API call,
start with that.
If it's
a simple
workflow, that's
that's all
you need.
Start simple
and decide
based on
the data
where the data
leads you,
or where
the problem
leads
you based
on the problem.
Build
complexity.
Don't start
with complex
multi-agent
workflow
based on again,
what do you see
from Excel,
YouTube,
or like a
lot of people
talking
about it,
not always.
You need
all those
like complex
things.
So start simple.
You don't really
need agents
for anything
and everything
that you're
doing.
Just a simple
model call
will mostly do
the things
with
a good prompt.
And then
if you need
go and build
agents,
this is like
a huge one,
even for me.
I have to keep
reminding
myself,
even if I'm
building
something like
a demo,
not everything
needs like
ten different
agents
running at
the same time.
The biggest
bottleneck in
AI right now
is in
the models.
It's evaluation
one.
Yes, 100%.
It becomes
more true
when you're
building,
complex agents,
which is not
just the models,
but models
plus tools
plus context.
So it is
interacting
with the
multiple
components
and they're like
multiple
layers involved.
And
most of our evals
these days are
mostly white,
white space.
Okay.
This looks good
this way
because to
be honest,
there is that
there hasn't
been a
standard way
to evaluate
agents or,
evaluate,
these
workflows.
But a lot
of these
technologies
and products
are built
in that
direction.
And it's
getting more
and more
important.
That's one thing
that we saw
in our agent
step,
Achievement
Agent demo
where
we asked it
to write
eval criteria.
So evals
are very,
very important.
I would
highly recommend
to evaluate
your agents
before
putting them
into production.
Don't just fly.
White
good vibes.
Okay,
this looks good.
And let me
put it
in production
because
high chance that
that somewhat
something could
break in
production.
You would
not even know
what caused
the error,
for these
agent workflows.
And then to
end it off,
I always ask
all our guests
this one
question.
So what is
the one
AI tool,
framework,
or concept that
you could
never give up?
Now, if you
would have
asked me
like two
months ago,
it would be very
different now.
I would say
like my
AI agents.
So my
AI agencies,
my interface
to any
and every AI
tool that I use,
I just
like Ping Monica
or my other
AI agents.
We want to do this,
and they
figure out
whatever tools
that they
want to use,
which also gets
into something
that we
talked about,
that all
these products
are being mostly
more
and more used
by agents
and not
just humans.
So my agents
is something
that I cannot
really live
without and
can
cannot give up
because they
are my interface
to pretty
much everything
that I'm
building
these days.
Sure.
This has been an
incredible
episode.
Thank you
so much
for coming
to the
Agent Factory.
Thanks.
It was great
to be here.
Thank you
for having me.
If you want
to build
what I showcased
and more,
check out
Addictive and
Agent CLI
in agents
platform.
That's your
way to go.
I'll be linking
everything
we mentioned
in the
description box
below, along
with a bunch of
viral articles
that Shubham
has written
on things
like the five
agent skill
design patterns,
as well
as The
Complete
Developer's
Guide
to Building
Agents
with skills.
Check out this
next episode
to see
all the cool
stuff
you can build
with Gemini CLI,
along with
Gemini
Suite Life.